Cleve Gray
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Photographs, circa 1934-2002, Series 8:; (Boxes 8-10; 1.15 linear ft.)
  - People, Cleve Gray (Box 8)
    - Portraits (photographers include: Cornelia Lavin, Alexander Liberman, Frances McLaughlin-Gill, and Nancy Tutko), circa 1960s-1980, (oversized material housed in Box 9) (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Portraits, 1984-1989, undated, (See also: Threnody, In Progress, Box 8, F 23-24) (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - In Studio, 1970s-1997, undated (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - With Francine, 1957, undated, (oversized material housed in Box 9) (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - With Francine, undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - With Francine and Sons, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - With Family and Friends (with baby Thaddeus, Irving Penn, photographer; with Francine and Hans Richter in Richter's studio), circa 1959, undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - With Others (University of Hartford, Honorary Doctor of Fine Arts degree), 1992 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - People, Others (Hans Richter?, Richter descendants),1996 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Places, Cleve Gray's Studio, undated, (See also: Cleve Gray in Studio, Box 8, F 32) (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, Cow, undated (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, Exhibition Installations (Box 8)
    - Threnody at Neuberger Museum of Art, State University of New York, College at Purchase, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Unidentified (Alexander Liberman, photographer) and "Century Masters: Cleve Gray, 43 Years of Work" at The Century Association, 1989-2002 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Negatives, Art Work by Cleve Gray (Box 8)
    - Paintings, undated, (2 folders; See also: Threnody, Box 8 F 47-49) (Box 8, Folder 43-44)
    - Paintings by Cleve Gray (destroyed), undated (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Photograph by Cleve Gray, Photo Abstraction, undated, (copy negative) (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Threnody ("contact #1" - "contact #4), circa 1972-1974 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Threnody ("contact #5" - "contact #8"), circa 1972-1974 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Threnody ("contact #9" - "contact #13"), circa 1972-1974 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Negatives, Illustrations for David Smith by David Smith: Sculpture and Writings, circa 1968 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Negatives, People - Cleve Gray, undated (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Transparencies, Artwork - Paintings by Cleve Gray, undated (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Oversize Photographs, Art Work by Cleve Gray, circa 1934, (See: Box 8, folder 20) (Box 9 (sol))
  - Oversize Photographs, Events, undated, (See: Box 8, folder 27) (Box 9 (sol))
  - Oversize Photographs, People, circa 1960s-1980s, undated, (See: Box 8, folders 30, 33) (Box 9 (sol))
  - Oversize Photographs, Illustrations for David Smith by David Smith: Sculpture and Writings, undated, (See: Box 8, folder 28) (Box 10 (sol))